Paolo MACULOTTI

Italian, born on January 14, 1980 Single paolo.maculotti@gmail.com (+33) 6 19 52 92 88

KEY QUALIFICATIONS

More than 7 years' experience as Contracts/Claims Manager, Negotiator, Legal Advisor – Specialized in International Business Law, Corporate Strategy and Contracts – Fluent and qualified in English, Spanish, French, Italian – Broad geographical mobility – Member of the Madrid Bar of attorneys.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Consilium – Worldwide – Since March 2011

Senior Consultant

Specialised in main Turnkey, Construction and Supply Contracts, expert in managing difficult contractual phases for complex projects, from tender to renegotiation, in order to secure budgets and recover control of projects' issues; Specialized in drafting and handling the claims and change orders; Undertaking of due diligence and compliance programmes; Evaluation of risks inherent in the international environment. Consilium focuses on the Metallurgical, Process Plants, Oil & Gas Industries and Construction Projects

Castaldi Mourre & Partners - France/Italy - Since March 2011

Senior Consultant and Lawyer

Advisor for contracts' negotiation and assisting clients involved in international projects

Technip – Middle East Region – United Arab Emirates – *July 2009 to September 2010* Legal Counsel

Follow-up of legal issues related to tendering activities – Responsible of the legal framework for the development of international Construction projects; Coordination with Chinese and Vietnamese national companies, launching of partnership, negotiations of agreements (MOU, HOA) and management of New Companies set-up – Focal point for Proposal and Procurement teams; dealing with legal aspects of Mergers and Acquisitions

CTJV – Technip Chiyoda Joint Venture, QCS Project – Qatar – May 2008 to June 2009 Contract Manager/Engineer

Contractual management of a World Class Multi Billions EPC Onshore LNG Project and analysis for Project and Start-up activities – Responsible of the legal framework for all project-related commercial risks and obligations: third-party obligations, project claim strategy and management, preservation of contractual rights/entitlements – Active support for the project team in any contractual and legal issues: planning, schedule, subcontracts, construction, interfaces, cost & finance. Compliance with Corporate and Project requirements, systems, procedures and budgets – Preparation, Administration and Follow-up of Project Changes in the work and of Client's Variations Requests/Orders – Monitoring of project Insurances and Insurance Claims – Assistance to project management with contract related notes – Administration of MOU, Procurement and Subcontractors procedures, Minutes of Meeting

Technip – Asia Pacific Region (TPGM) – Malaysia – *January 2007 to April 2008* Lawyer for Oil & Gas and Renewable Energies' Projects

Follow-up of Joint Ventures and Consortiums' related cases (EPCM and FEED contracts) – In charge of Corporate matters, litigations and assistance of the companies in South-East Asia and Australia – Preparation and control of tender/grant contractual documents for work or services on designated projects – Contract documentation draft/review, negotiation/preparation and evaluation of ITT, PO Contracts, legal documentation, memoranda and contractual/commercial notes – Administration of Bonds, Parent Company Guarantees and insurance matters; resolution of contractual claims and disputes – Evaluation of the effectiveness of work methods in use – Cooperation and integration with project accounts/finance, tax and insurance departments for survey of applicable practices/procedures

Castaldi Mourre & Sprague – International Law Firm – France – June to December 2005 Junior Lawyer and Consultant

Preparation of international contracts and companies' charters – Draft of the conclusions for litigations' cases, definition of the strategy with the clients and corporate advisory – Processing of the fillings with the Competition Authority – Financial analysis and case-building investigations.

SIMOMC – Simulation of the WTO Negotiations on International Trade – Canada – 2004/2005

<u>Team Leader and Supervisor</u> – Recruitment, training and coordination of the French delegation – Organization of the simulation – Funds rising – Chairman and Expert of Declarations' drafting.

French Embassy – Economic Bureau (DREE) – Chile – September 2003 to February 2004

Assistant to the Commercial Delegate of the Energy and Industrials sector – Market researches and corporate guidance – In charge of the visit of the Foreign Trade minister – Participation in the drafting sessions of the commercial treaty between France and Chile – Draft of the official Guide on Renewable Energies in South America (Official publication in 2004).

National Model of United Nations – United States of America – April 2003/2004

<u>Chief of staff and coordinator</u> of the 28 members' group of Sciences Po University – Delegate to the ECOSOC, IOM and to the General Assembly – Coordinator of the UN University Day in Paris: conferences and job fair – In charge of the initiative's budget and sponsorships.

EDUCATION

Comparative Law Institute of Paris – 2005/2006 – **France**

Comparative Law Diploma, French-Spanish Juridical Terminology Diploma Arabic Law and Contracts, Petroleum Law and Contracts, Law of Energies, Contracts' drafting Thesis: "Analysis and Evolution of Petroleum Contracts: the Renegotiation Clauses' handling"

Paris I Panthéon Sorbonne, Sciences Po Paris, Cornell University – 2004/2005 – France/USA Joint Master Degree in Global Business Law - Bilingual English-French

International Contracts and Litigation, Companies and Corporate Law, Antitrust and Competition, Intellectual Property Law, WTO Law and Settlement rules, Global Regulation

Sciences Po Paris – 2002/2004 – France

Master in International Business - Bilingual French-Spanish Leading French Institute for Economics, Business, Political and Social Sciences

Alma Mater Studiorum University of Bologna –1999/2005 – Italy

Master in International Sciences and Diplomacy, 110/110

Arnaldo High School, Brescia – Italy

High school degree (literature) July 1999

LANGUAGES

Arabic Intermediate level. Student at the French Institute of Oriental Languages

ACTIVITIES AND INTERESTS

Bureau des Elèves, Main Sciences-Po Students' Association (BDE)

2002/2003 Executive Board member: in charge of events, parties, sponsorships and conferences/fairs. Advanced Open Water SCUBA Diver; Track and field; Ski; Swimming.